AKRAM MOHAMED

Senior Mobile Software Engineer

Contact



Address:

5th Settlement, Cairo, Egypt



Email:

akram.mohamed.dev @gmail.com



Phone:

+2/0109-2053-581



Portfolio Hyperlink



GitHub Hyperlink



LinkedIn Hyperlink

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

Dart

Kotlin

Swift

Java

C++

TypeScript

Frameworks & Libraries:

Flutter

Swift UI

UIKit

Android SDK

Nodejs

Jetpack Compose

Databases:

Firebase

SOLite

Mongo

Concepts:

CI/CD

RASP

Unit Testing

Agile Tools:

JIRA

Azure

Trello

Professional Summary:

A mobile software engineer with an experience of 3 years in mobile development using Flutter, Android and iOS SDKs. Built and contributed to six live apps on stores. Seeking for developing higher levels of structured mega projects through teamwork using best practices and design patterns.

Working Experience:

Etisalat Misr

Full-Time Senior Mobile Software Engineer May 2022 - Present



Working on My Etisalat Android/iOS native mobile application as a senior mobile software engineer mentoring junior developers and reviewing their code.

Working on Etisalat Cash Flutter mobile app as a senior Flutter developer, maintaining the app and its SDK in My Etisalat native application.

Working on separating My Etisalat iOS application into modules such as Etisalat Marketplace, Etisalat Authenticator, Etisalat Network and integrate them to My Etisalat main application.

Conducting assessments with solution architects to start new features, refactoring code and adding internal features to help other developers.



Tamra Capital

Part-Time Flutter Developer

July 2023 - Present



Working on Tamra Capital Flutter mobile application as a senior Flutter developer, mentoring junior flutter developers.

Maintaining application, fixing bugs, adding security features, for example: RASP solution, Root Detection and SSL Pinning.

Architecting the application, reviewing the code, giving consultation to business owners and improving customer experience.



Rumbling Games Studio

Full-Time Junior Flutter Developer

July 2021 - March 2022



Working as a junior flutter developer to develop a smart home app. Also, working as an IoT engineer developing programs for micro boards, such as: ESP8266, using Arduino with C++.

Working as a back-end developer using Node.js on a VPS and Firebase Cloud Functions. Also, working as a front-end developing the company's website.

Freelancing Experience:



United Business Solutions

Freelancer Mid-Level Flutter Developer

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022



Developed a full-customized internal Flutter application (UBS: Elite) that measures the company's drivers' trips, check-ins, cars fuel consumption and distances traveled.

O Dream Company

Freelancer Mid-Level Flutter Developer

Apr 2022 - May 2022



Enhanced two live apps' performance, UI and solved their bugs (Dream App, Jeras). Also, added new capabilities like: notifications, cloud functions, enhanced user experience and revamped the application.

Education:

Information Technology Institute (ITI)

Front-End and Cross-Platform Mobile Application

Jan 2021 - April 2021

A 3-month scholarship in ITI, Front-End and Cross-Platform Mobile App Development Track. In which, I learnt to build websites with web frameworks like: React and Angular, and mobile applications with Flutter and React-Native.

Grade: A+ (Ranked First)

Bachelor's in Petroleum Engineering

Faculty of Petroleum and Mining Engineering, Suez Univ.

Oct 2015 - Aug 2020

Grade: C+ (78.07%)

Live Projects:

My Etisalat iOS/Android Native App

Etisalat Misr

Etisalat Cash Flutter App

Etisalat Misr

Tamra Capital Fintech Flutter App Tamra Capital

UBS Elite Internal Driver Data Flutter App **UBS: Elite**

Oream Flutter App **Dream Company**

SensoFox Smart Home Flutter App **Rumbling Games Studio**

Volunteering Experience:

American Association of Petroleum Geologists

Android Developer (Java)

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019

References:

Eng. Ahmed Fouad

Rumbling Games CEO 0109-406-9463

Eng. Mahmoud Fathelbab Etisalat Digital Manager

0112-167-0285

Mr. AbdulAziz AlMshali

Dream Company CEO +966-50327-8910

Eng. Mostafa Maklad

Tamra Capital CTO +966-54384-8424

